<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Marketing Calendar Blog</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 22:16:59 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 22:16:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Mired in the Details</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When starting a project it always feels like I have a very clear vision of what the final product will look like.  The truth is that there are a million little details that are not yet contemplated at the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows…if I knew how many details were involved, would I start the project?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been considering some feedback from some mockup screen shots.  Someone pointed out that it is difficult to see, on the calendar, which steps belong to tactics and which tactics belong to events.  And the feedback is good feedback.  It is hard to see how things go together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this initial view you can see that all of the green tactics blend together.  Then the gray steps float around, but don’t seem to be associated with their tactics (all of the steps actually belong to tactics).  The feedback is definitely good.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/calendar_design_screen_shot_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Initial mockup example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result I’ve been trying to do some color coding of items on the calendar to try to make it clear that the items are associated.  I’m moving toward something that’s a little more reasonable in terms of color schemes.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/calendar_design_screen_shot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Calendar experiment in design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What might not be immediately obvious is that calendar items don’t “belong” to each other still.  For example from the 1st through the 3rd is the &lt;em&gt;Thu Email&lt;/em&gt; that has a green background.  That tactic owns the “Selections Complete” step on the 1st, the “HTML Complete” step on the 2nd, and the “Deliver” step on the 3rd.  I would like for each of those steps to appear underneath the &lt;em&gt;Thu Email&lt;/em&gt; tactic.  It gets messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to work through those sorts of details to improve the look.  I’m not sure if this is the best use of my time.  Perhaps I should punt this down the road and figure I’ll hire someone to do a better visual design?  Or maybe I should go ahead and work on this now so I can maake it usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many details to consider and they aren’t apparent at the beginning.  It’s easy to get mired in the details when I should probably be worrying more about getting enough of the site working that someone can actually use it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/getting-mired-in-the-details</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/getting-mired-in-the-details</guid>
        
        
        <category>calendar</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting Up a Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I knew up front that I wanted to set up a blog to track my work as I develop The Marketing Calendar.  And I wanted to start the blogging process before I even have an application up and running.  The plan is to write the system based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyonrails.org/&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt;.  There are more languages involved, specifically &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeescript.org/&quot;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt;, but the primary platform is Rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the Rails system is oriented around basic reading and writing to/from a database (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete&quot;&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt;).  That means there are frequent changes to the database structure.  I know from experience that during development I often like to reset the database so that it’s completely fresh.  Additionally there’s the possibility of making a mistake that wipes out the database on my development system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, I don’t trust my local database during early development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I didn’t really want to start creating blog entries in a database that I don’t trust.  I wanted to know that if I take some time to write a blog entry then that entry needs to be saved reliably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In doing a little research I found that creating &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/basics&quot;&gt;markdown files&lt;/a&gt; is pretty straightforward. Having text files on the hard drive feels like a pretty reliable way to save my blog entries.  In addition to my regular system backups, the markdown files will be included as part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;revision control&lt;/a&gt;.  And, initially, the files can live anywhere on my hard drive…they don’t have to be part of a “real” application.  I like that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; text editor.  And Atom comes, by default, with a markdown preview package built-in.  Hit ctrl+shift+m and you can preview the post while you’re typing the markdown.  I like that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; can generate your blog as static web pages from your markdown files.  I followed the instructions in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/jekyll-rails/&quot;&gt;helpful guide to setting up Jekyll with Rails&lt;/a&gt;.  The only issue I had was that the site suggests specifying Jekyll 2.5.3 in your Gemfile.  I was getting an error message: &lt;em&gt;Liquid Exception: Failed to get header.&lt;/em&gt;  Eventually I found that the current version of Jekyll is 3.1.2. When I changed my Gemfile then Jekyll generated the site correctly.  I like that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I can write blog posts that will be persistent before I have a real application.  The entries are also included as part of my regular backups and revision control. Those posts aren’t going anywhere.  And I like that!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/setting-up-a-blog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/setting-up-a-blog</guid>
        
        
        <category>calendar</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 15:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/jekyll/update/2016/03/14/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/jekyll/update/2016/03/14/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started on the Marketing Calendar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my day job I have heard for years from our internal team that our customers want a marketing calendar.  Since I’m more on the technical side I have always heard that this is a problem.  However I haven’t heard much from anyone about what a solution to the &lt;em&gt;we don’t have a marketing calendar&lt;/em&gt; problem might actually look like.  We also don’t have the internal resources to work through the planning and design a project like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have watched over the years, I have come across some example of what people are doing to manage their projects.  I wouldn’t even describe their work as &lt;em&gt;creating a calendar&lt;/em&gt; – they’re really just trying to manage projects.  Those projects happen to be oriented around marketing campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty different view of the world than a standard grid-like calendar.  It’s actually &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gantt_chart&quot;&gt;a Gantt chart&lt;/a&gt;.  It is great to have a Gantt view that lets you see the status of projects and their sub-tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is also very helpful to have a calendar view of everything that is going on.  A produce like Microsoft Project can offer a web-based calendar view of the world too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/a8a39edf-d322-4c8d-b47f-5524aa854ac5/image/file/33121/0/Professional_Calendar_Actions.png?Id=33121 =50x50&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Project on the web&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With a standard project management tool you don’t have an easy way to recreate repetitive mini-projects (like an emailing campaign that has several steps, each with their own due dates).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employees/managers all have different views of the world, filtering to different levels of abstraction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone who is involved, or interested, in a given task should be able to get updates on the task either as they happen or as part of a daily digest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team members do tend to want to add comments to items on the plan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A marketing calendar isn’t really just one project–it is an ongoing, never-ending series of projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the marketing perspective, projects are more about coordinating deadlines than allocating resources.  We care when tasks are supposed to be complete so that our event can go live.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We also want to know how the similar project worked out last year so we have an idea of what sort of sales we can expect this year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team members are definitely not all in the same department and often are not even in the same company because vendors are involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 14:00:25 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/getting-started-on-the-marketing-calendar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.themarketingcalendar.com/blog/getting-started-on-the-marketing-calendar</guid>
        
        
        <category>calendar</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
